A Guide to the T.S. Eliot Collection ca. 1892-1986, and undated
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
T.S. Eliot Collection ca. 1892-1986, and undated
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12248
This collection consists of ca. sixty items (one Hollinger box, ca. .5 linear feet).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items were originally part of a collection of books and papers owned by Donald Gallup and sold to the University of Virginia Library by Waiting for Godot Books, Hadley, Massachusetts; non-book items were transferred to the Manuscripts Division on July 26, 2002.
Biographical/Historical Information
Donald Gallup was the Curator of the Collection of American Literature at Yale University Library, New Haven, Connecticut, and a member of the T.S. Eliot Society.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of ca. sixty items (one Hollinger box), ca. 1892-1986, and undated, all pertaining to author T.S. Eliot and his life and work, including manuscripts or copies of manuscripts, correspondence, photographs, and memorabilia.
Arrangement
The folders are arranged in chronological order.
Contents List
- Photograph of T.S. Eliot as a child [ca. 1892]
- Photograph of Eastern Point, Gloucester, Massachusetts [ca. 1900]
- Harvard University Student Card belonging to T.S. Eliot, signed by bursar 1913 September 23
- Notes by T.S. Eliot on Aristotle's Analyticorum Posteriorum, page 55 [ca. 1913]
  The book was owned by Eliot in his post-graduate years at Harvard University (a photostatic copy with a typed note about the original in the Widener Library).
- Harvard University Tuition Receipt made out to T.S. Eliot, stamped paid on February 5, 1913 by bursar 1913 February 5
- "The Death of Saint Narcissus" by T.S. Eliot [1915 October]
  This is a photostatic copy of the original canceled galley proof which was scheduled for publication in Poetry but withdrawn before publication.
- Photograph of T.S. Eliot, possibly taken on a Cunard Line sea voyage [ca. 1921]
- "The Prophet of the Waste Land - T.S. Eliot" by Walter Hanks Shaw [ca. 1928]
  Typed Manuscript (carbon), 6 pages
- "Marina" by T.S. Eliot 1930 May 9
  Photostatic copies of the Typescript and Manuscript versions; and a Photostatic copy of a Postscript of a letter from Eliot to Sir Michael Sadler, describing his writing method in the poem
- Postal card from T.S. Eliot to the Librarian of Congress, Herbert Putnam 1934 & 1938
  Eliot writes regarding "Ezra Pound: His Metric and Poetry," a negative photostatic copy; with a typed note from a Library of Congress cataloger to D.C. Gallup about the postal card
- "Some Uses of the Poetry of T.S. Eliot" by Elizabeth Wheeler Manwaring [late 1930's], TMS, 13 pp.
- Correspondence of T.S. Eliot and Ashley Dukes, Martin Browne, and Frank V. Morley 1938 March-April
  Typescript Copies, regarding the original production of Eliot's play, The Family Reunion
- Photograph of T.S. Eliot by E. McKnight Kauffer, London 1939
- Photograph of T.S. Eliot seated at a typewriter, taken by Jarlas Foto copyright by Ahlen & Akerlind Studio, Stockholm 1942
- Photographs of Little Gidding Church by Donald Gallup 1943 February
- The Columbia Workshop Script for readings from T.S. Eliot's Four Quartets1946 March 16
  These include "Burnt Norton" read by John Hall Wheelock and "Little Gidding" read by James Johnson Sweeney.
- Emilio Ceechi, Italian scholar and Eliot translator, to Bernard Wall 1946 December 23
  Autograph Post Card Signed, mentioning a recent long and interesting talk with Eliot
- "Incontro Con T.S. Eliot" by Emilio Cecchi [1946], TMS, 5 pp.
- Donald Gallup to [John Cook] Wyllie 1947 June 1
  Thanks him for the McGregor Seminar programs and notes about the Italian translations in Sud
- "A Personal Anthology" by T.S. Eliot [1948] February 22, TMS, 18 pp.
  Might have been written for a BBC appearance, then a copy was sent to Donald Gallup, who read the text at Yale University.
- Photograph of T.S. Eliot, publicity shot by Angus McBean, Eliot shown seated, from the waist up [ca. 1940's]
- Jeannette Lowrey to Van Allen Bradley, Literary Editor, of The Daily News1950 October 12
  Lowrey urges him to listen to the lectures of T.S. Eliot, praising his literary allusions, and suggests he do an interview with Eliot while he is at the University of Chicago, Typed Letter Signed
- Photograph of T.S. Eliot standing before a tall bookcase, probably taken when Eliot delivered a series of lectures at the University of Chicago [ca. 1950]
- Yale Reports on the Arts & Sciences 1959 March 4
  "T.S. Eliot: The Four Quartets A Conversation for Television between Edith Kerr and Norman Holmes Pearson, 7 pages
- "The Art of Fiction XXIV: T.S. Eliot" An Interview in The Paris Review conducted by Donald Hall [1959]
  Corrected Page Proof
- Correspondence concerning The T.S. Eliot Newsletter and related topics, chiefly between Donald Gallup, Curator Collection of American Literature, Yale University Library, and Editor Shyamal Bagchee 1973-1982
- Selected Prose of T.S. Eliot, edited with introduction by Frank Kermode [1975]
  Uncorrected Page Proof, Electrostatic Copy (2 folders)
- Postcards from the National Portrait Gallery featuring an abstract painting of Eliot by Patrick Heron and a plaster cast of a bust of Eliot by Sir Jacob Epstein [1970's]
- T.S. Eliot Society Membership Certificate for Donald Gallup 1986 September 26
- "Please inscribe for Miss Emily Hal[e?][blank] Prufrock" in ink and signed by T.S. Eliot as "Done TSE" in pencil n.d., AN
- Photographs of "The Dry Salvages," and Exhibition of Eliot books by Donald Gallup at [Yale University?], Magdalene College Hall post card photograph, and T.S. Eliot portrait snapshot n.d.
- "La Terre Mise A Nu" n.d., TMS, carbon 9 pp.
- "Notes on Eliot's Epigraphs" from Jane Worthington's typescript "The Epigraphs to the Poetry of T.S. Eliot" n.d., TMS, 3 pp.